zoneedit.com 2014-10-18

# Advanced DNS Management - Easy, web-based domain manager - ZoneEdit.com

This Privacy Statement discloses the privacy practices for ZoneEdit, LLC. ("ZoneEdit", "We" or "Us") and how it treats the information that ZoneEdit collects and receives, including information related to your past use of ZoneEdit products and services. This policy does not apply to the practices of companies that ZoneEdit does not own or control, or to people that ZoneEdit does not employ or manage.

1\. The information collected by ZoneEdit.  
2\. Communications from ZoneEdit  
3\. How information collected by ZoneEdit is used.  
4\. Correction/Updating Personal Information  
5\. Opting Out  
6\. Terminated ZoneEdit Accounts  
7\. Use of the ZoneEdit Website by Persons Under Age 13  
8\. Linking to Third-Party Websites  
9\. Security  
10\. Changes to Our Privacy Statement  
11\. Final Statement

1 Information Collected by ZoneEdit  
We will not knowingly use information collected on this website in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. ZoneEdit collects information from our users at several different points on our website. For purposes of this Privacy Statement, "Personally Identifiable Information" refers to information that can directly identify an individual; for example, such information may include an individual's name, mailing address, phone number or email address.

1.1 Information that Is Automatically Collected  
We use IP addresses, with the help of a business partner, to analyze trends, administer the website, track users' movements, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to Personally Identifiable Information.

1.2 Information that Is Collected by Cookies  
A cookie is a piece of data stored on a user's hard drive containing information about that user. By setting a cookie on our website, the user would not have to log in with a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our website. If a user rejects the cookie, they may still use our website. The only drawback to this is that the user will be limited in some areas of our website. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our website. Some of our business partners use cookies on our website (for example, advertisers); however, we have no access to or control over these cookies.

1.3 Information that Is Actively Submitted to ZoneEdit  
Registrations and Orders. In order to register a domain name or order services from this website, a user must create an account and complete a registration process. During the account creation process, a user must provide contact information (such as name and email address) so that we can stay in touch with our users. This information is also used to fulfill order and registration requests. To pay for a domain name registration or for other service ordered, a user must provide contact information (such as name and shipping address) and financial information (such as a credit card number and its expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes, with the help of our business partner, and to fill users' orders. If we have trouble processing an order, this contact information is used to get in touch with the user. 

1.4 Third-Party Advertisers on ZoneEdit's Website  
We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads (using methods that include Pixel Tags and Clear Gifs) when you visit our website. Third-party advertising companies also separately place or recognize a cookie file on your browser in the course of delivering advertisements to this website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. 

1.5 Information ZoneEdit Obtains from Third Parties  
Supplemental Information Collected. In certain circumstances, in order for our website to properly fulfill its obligation to our users, it is necessary for us to supplement the information we receive with information from third party sources. 

ZoneEdit Accounts Created by a Third Party on Your Behalf. If you received your domain name from someone else, without registering for it yourself, your domain name may belong to a third party. If the administrator of a company with whom you have a business relationship (e.g., your web hosting provider) registers your domain name for you, the administrator may have access to the domain name and may be able to edit your ZoneEdit profile, reset your password, and manage the ZoneEdit account without your additional consent. In addition to the terms mentioned in this Privacy Policy, an account created by a third party allows any of your Personally Identifiable Information within that account to be available to that third party as if it were you. We have no access to or control over the third party to prevent its disclosure of your information. 

2 Communications from ZoneEdit  
Welcome Emails and General Correspondence. We send a welcoming email to the email address associated with the account a user has created to verify the users password and username. This process is designed to prevent e-mail addresses from being used without permission in the creation of a ZoneEdit account. Established users will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, and a newsletter. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive some of these types of communications. Please see our opt-out options below. 

Site and Service Updates. We send the user website and service announcement updates. Users are not permitted to unsubscribe from service announcements, which contain important information about the website and/or service. We may communicate with users to provide services that users request or to discuss issues relating to their account. 

Surveys & Contests. From time-to-time our website requests information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and, as such, the user has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code, age level). 

3 How Information Collected by ZoneEdit Is Used  
Demographic Information. We will share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers. The aggregated demographic information is not linked to any Personally Identifiable Information that can identify any individual person. 

Communicating with Our Users. We use Personally Identifiable Information (such as your name, telephone number or email address) to communicate with our users when they have questions, concerns or comments about their accounts or the services that we provide. If you contact us, we may or may not delete your emails or voicemails to us. 

Information Shared With Third Parties. We share information with third parties as required by ICANN and in order to give our customers access to a great variety of services. Specifically, we may do the following: 

  * Submit the name, postal address, e-mail address, and phone numbers associated with the registrant, administrative, technical and billing contacts of a domain name to the appropriate Registry or registration database. This information is included in a publicly available 'Whois' database, in accordance with ICANN rules. This sharing of information is required by ICANN rules.
  * Use a credit card processing company to bill users for goods and services. These companies do not use Personally Identifiable Information for any use other than credit card processing; however, we will not be responsible or liable for use of the information required by credit card companies in contravention of their policies, contractual obligations or general good business procedures. 
  * Partner with third parties who provide services to our users. When the user signs up for or agrees to receive a specific service provided by the third party (i.e. PostMasterDirect advertisements), we share the information that is needed for the third party to provide the services. 
  * Share the publicly available domain contact information submitted by our users for inclusion in the Whois database with third parties. We do not control the use of this Personally Identifiable Information by third parties.
  * Share your Personally Identifiable Information with other entities that are owned by ZoneEdit, that own ZoneEdit, or have some sort of corporate ownership relationship with ZoneEdit.

Bulk Access. As an ICANN-accredited registrar, ZoneEdit is required to make WHOIS data available to a third party that enters into a bulk access agreement. ICANN allows individuals to opt-out (using the account management panel) of their WHOIS information being made available to third parties through bulk access; however, companies, businesses, and other organizations do not have the option to choose not to have their information made available to such a third party under a bulk access agreement.

Addressing Legal Issues. Further, we provide Personally Identifiable Information to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims. Further, we believe it is necessary to share Personally Identifiable Information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of ZoneEdit's terms of use, or as otherwise required by law.

Sale or Transfer of ZoneEdit. If all or a portion of ZoneEdit is transferred, sold, merged, ceases operations, goes bankrupt, or is otherwise involved in a transaction where the ownership or management of ZoneEdit is changed (individually or collectively, a "Transaction") then your Personally Identifiable Information or other user information may be transferred or assigned to a third party as part of the Transaction. 

4 Correction/Updating Personal Information  
Users must provide accurate and correct contact information (name, postal address, e-mail address, phone number) for their domain name(s) Registrant, Administrative, Technical and Billing contacts, which will be listed in a publicly accessible 'Whois' database, in compliance with ICANN rules. If a user's Personally Identifiable Information changes (such as a zip code), or if a user no longer desires ZoneEdit's services, we will provide a way to correct, update or remove that user's personal data provided to us. This can usually be done under online account management (on your own) or by emailing our user Support Group for assistance.

5 Opting Out  
Users are provided an opportunity to "opt-out" of having their information used for purposes not directly related to the services they request. Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter or promotional materials from us may opt-out of receiving these communications by replying and typing "unsubscribe" in the subject line in the email or email your request to dotnews@zoneedit.com.

6 Terminated ZoneEdit Accounts  
If your ZoneEdit account is terminated or cancelled (regardless of whether it was voluntary), all of your Personally Identifiable Information will remain on our servers. We retain and use your Personally Identifiable Information as necessary to enforce our policies or to address contractual issues, and may contact you for future marketing or promotional purposes. 

7 Use of the ZoneEdit Website by Persons Under Age 13  
This website is not intended for use by anyone under the age of thirteen (13), and any individual under such age should not provide us with Personally Identifiable Information. We do not knowingly contact, market to, solicit, collect or use Personally Identifiable Information from or about any individual under the age of 13. It is possible that by fraud or deception we may receive information pertaining to children under 13. If we are notified of that we have personal information regarding a person under the age of 13, as soon as we reasonably verify the information, we will either obtain parental consent or otherwise delete the information from the account and/or service. However, the information may remain on a log in our servers. If you want to notify us of our receipt of information by children under 13, please do so by emailing us at: abuse@zoneedit.com.

8 Linking to Third-Party Websites  
This website contains links to other websites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other websites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our website and to read the Privacy Statements of each and every website that collects Personally Identifiable Information. This Privacy Statement applies solely to information collected by this website. 

9 Security  
ZoneEdit recognizes the importance of security for all Personally Identifiable Information collected by our Web site and we use recognized industry practices to protect your information. Unfortunately, no transmission of information over the Internet can be completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your Personally Identifiable information, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to our Site from your PC or through an Internet Service Provider, and any transmission is at your own risk. In the event we request or transmit sensitive information, such as credit card information, we use industry standard, secure socket layer ("SSL") encryption. 

10 Changes to Our Privacy Statement  
This Privacy Policy may change, and use of information that we gather now is subject to the Privacy Policy that is in effect as of the time of use. You are responsible for periodically checking our Privacy Policy. If we make minor changes to this Privacy Policy and the new uses are related to uses we disclose in this statement, the changes will be immediately effective upon posting the revised Privacy Policy to the website. If we make a material change to how we use the information you provide and the new uses are unrelated to uses we disclose in this statement, we will communicate the changes in a prominent notice on this Site prior to its implementation and provide you the opportunity to change your marketing preferences to opt-out of such use. You are responsible for periodically checking our Privacy Policy. You may opt-out of any posted change to our collection, use or disclosure of your personal information by submitting your request via our support form. However, if you opt-out from providing information related to the services you request, we may not be able to provide you with the services.

11) Final Statement  
ZoneEdit will use your information in accordance with the Privacy Statement that is currently in effect. If you have any questions about the security at our website, you can send an email to [security@zoneedit.com](mailto:security@zoneedit.com).
